# CARLOS FERNÁNDEZ SAN MILLÁN

**♀** In der Warthütte 9, 69181, Leimen, Germany

% cormite.com in linkedin.com/in/carlosfernandezsanmillan y cormite Q github.com/cormite

Last Updated: 7th Apr, 2020



Systems and Virtualization Engineer with 10+ years of experience in international IT enterprise environments. Managed large scale virtualization and storage infrastructures, proficient in VMware and NetApp with deep passion for enterprise-wide management and optimization. Ability to work as a team, experience in international multidisciplinary groups, primarily in education and research environments, leadership and fast learning ability. Always interested in challenging projects, as well as close interaction with manufacturers.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Systems and Virtualization Engineer

#### **European Molecular Biology Laboratory - EMBL**

October 2018 - Ongoing

♥ Heidelberg, Germany

## Systems Engineer

#### European Molecular Biology Laboratory - EMBL

October 2012 - October 2018

♥ Heidelberg, Germany

- Responsible of VMware Cluster (26 physical hosts & 650 VMs)
   Migration from ESX 4.1 to ESXi 5.1, 5.5, 6.0, 6.5 and 6.7 (VMware vSphere Enterprise Plus). Consolidation of VMware Clusters in Heidelberg, Rome, and Barcelona; managed from Heidelberg's HQ. Responsible of the High Performance, GPU Driven, VDI infrastructure. Planned, configured and administered vSAN for the VDI cluster. In charge of the virtualization backup with Veeam Backup & Replication.
- NetApp administration [Data ONTAP until 9.6] [14 nodes ≈ 6 PB]
   Management of volumes, qtrees, policies (export, QoS, quota, snapshots), network interfaces. Monitoring the 14 node cluster to ensure optimal performance. Migrated qtrees and volumes from the legacy 7-Mode cluster to Data ONTAP.
- Other responsibilities

Datacenter management. Linux Support. Management and support of application such as Alfresco and Owncloud. Development of tools in python to consume APIs. Management of central infrastructure with Foreman, Puppet and Git. Monitoring infrastructure with Zabbix.

## IT Manager

#### Digital Arts & Designers, S.L.

**#** July 2010 - September 2012

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

Management of IT Projects. Linux Administration. Server Management. Networking Management. Monitoring and keeping infrastructure in optimal conditions. Responsible of purchasing technical equipment and keeping good relations with providers.

## Freelance System Administrator

#### **FIFA**

## June 2010 - July 2010

Pretoria & Johannesburg, South Africa

System administrator of Referee Channel, an e-learning platform based on web and video-streaming for FIFA Refereeing Department during the 2010 FIFA World Cup.

#### **Previous Jobs / Companies**

m June 2002 - May 2010

- Jan 2009 May 2010 | Systems administrator, Neuronal Software S.L.
- Mar 2008 Dec 2008 | Media Producer & System Administrator, Univ. of Las Palmas de G.C.
- Dec 2005 Feb 2008 | IT Consultant Freelance
- Oct 2005 Nov 2005 | Technical officer, Gran Canaria Espacio Digital
- Sep 2004 Jun 2005 | Consultant, Gran Canaria Campus junior entrepreneurship
- Jun 2002 Jul 2002 | Project Manager & Developer, La Provincia, Diario de Las Palmas
- Sep 1997 Sep 1999 | Laboratory Assistant, University of San Francisco

## **STRENGTHS**

**Linux Administration** 

**VMware Administration** 

NetApp Administration

Veeam Backup & Recovery

vSAN

Scripting

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Virtualization: VMware vSphere, VMware Horizon, OpenNebula, oVirt
- Storage: NetApp, QNap, Synology
- Backup: TSM, Veeam
- ERP: SAP
- Network: Fortigate, Extreme Networks, Netgear, Linksys, MicroTik, TP-Link, Ubiquity, ZyXEL, D-Link,
   NAM.
- Operating Systems: RedHat, CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, SuSE
- Services: LDAP, DHCP, DNS
- Automation: Foreman, Puppet, Ansible, Scripting
- Containers: Docker
- Container's Orchestration: Kubernetes

# **CERTIFICATES**

VMware Certified Associate - Data Center Virtualization

#### **VMware**

₩ Dec 2013

Credential ID 12011513-BE5E-90361323E2E7

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

## **Technical Engineering in Computer Science**

#### University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

**2000 - 2005** 

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

Activities and Societies: Gran Canaria Campus Junior Enterpreneurship

## **BSc Computer Science**

#### School of Arts and Science, University of San Francisco

**1996 - 2000** 

♀ San Francisco, California

Activities and Societies: USF Men's Soccer Team.

#### **Summer Courses**

#### University of California, Berkeley

**Summer 1998** 

Parkeley, California

Physics and Computer Architecture.

#### **Professional Instructor-Led Training**

- 03-2019 Kubernetes Fundaments & Operations Bundle (Amazic via Evenbrite)
- 09-2016 VMware vRealize Automation: Install, Configure, Manage [V7.0] (VMWAREVRICM7) (QA Limited)
- 05-2016 VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage plus Optimize and Scale Fast Track [V6.0] (VMware)
- 07-2015 IBM Tivoli Storage Manager 7.1.1 Implementation and Administration (QA Limited)
- 10-2014 Clustered Data ONTAP 8.2 Administration [NA DCADM] (Fast Lane)
- 11-2013 Data ONTAP 7-Mode Administration [NA D7ADM] (Fast Lane)

#### **Online Training**

- 03-2020 | Essential Container Concepts
- 02-2020 | Beginner's Guide to Containers and Orchestration
- 02-2020 | Ansible Quick Start
- 09-2018 | Puppet Quick Start
- 09-2018 | DevOps Essentials
- 08-2018 | Mastering The Linux Command Line
- 08-2018 | VIM The Improved Editor
- 08-2018 | Git Quick Start
- 12-2013 | Data ONTAP 7-Mode Fundamentals
- 07-2013 | Data ONTAP 8.1.1 7-Mode New Features
- 07-2013 | Data ONTAP License Key Replacement Scenarios
- 07-2013 | Introduction to NetApp Products
- 07-2013 | NetApp Transition Fundamentals
- 07-2013 | Technical Overview of Licensing in Data ONTAP 8.2
- 07-2013 | What's New in Data ONTAP 8.2 Licensing

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Learning Potential Team Work
Organization Flexibility
Professionalism Responsibility
MultiTasking Work Under Pressure
Initiative Problem Solving Proactive

Curiosity

# **LANGUAGES**

Social Skills

Spanish - Native English - Full Prof. Proficiency Galician Portuguese German



# **OTHERS**

- Driving License B
- SSI Diver Level 3 (MID 312710)

11-2016 - Specialty Diver

11-2016 - Dry Suit Diver

10-2016 - Enriched Air Nitrox

09-2016 - Perfect Buoyancy

11-2015 - Mission Deep Ocean Ranger

11-2010 - Open Water Diver

# **REFERENCES**

Dr. Rupert Lück, Head of IT.

@ European Molecular Biology Laboratory

■ lueck@embl.de

Prof. Dr. Cayetano Guerra Artal, Professor of Computer Science & Artificial Inteligence

@ University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

# **RECOMMENDATIONS**

Available upon request

## **PROJECTS**

#### Referee Channel

#### Digital Arts & Designers S.L.

m October 2010 - October 2012

#### International

- Referee Channel is a classification system of all game situations occurred in competition's matches which can be consulted from anywhere in the world without having to duplicate resources, allowing to establish a reliable and proactive communication system between all members of an organization. I was in charge of the server infrastructure and correct operation of the application.
- This tool was used by several institutions and during several competitions in these countries: Colombia, Spain, South Africa, Russia, USA
  - 4th South American Under 20 Futsal World Cup Championship. Itagüí (Colombia)
  - I-International Planet of Football, and Technology organized by Royal Spanish Soccer Federation. Madrid (Spain)
  - 2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa. Pretoria, (South Africa)
  - Russian Soccer Federation. Moscow (Russia)
  - CONCACAF Gold Cup 2010. New York (USA)

## \_\_\_\_\_

#### 112 Accesible

#### University of Las Palmas & Cátedra Telefónica

# June 2011 - November 2011

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

• 112 Accessible is a winning project of the prize from Cátedra Telefónica developed in the University of Las Palmas to help the emergency services to be more accessible to people who can't contact the 112 Emergency Center by voice call. I organized and produced the contents for 112 Accessible

## **IESCampus**

#### **Neuronal Software S.L.**

m June 2008 - June 2010

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

• IESCampus is an innovative educational website where you find all the resources necessary to achieve quality training in Secondary Education and Baccalaureate. IESCampus includes the full syllabus of the subjects, providing an excellent educational tool for students, and their teachers and parents

#### Prometeo

#### University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

# July 2007 - June 2010

♦ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

• E-learning application for the University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, based on web and video streaming, in compliance with Bologna Process.